Inventory of the J. Franklin Ray papers, 1946-1947
Hoover Institution Archives
J. Franklin Ray papers
1946-1947
76054
Hoover Institution Archives
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Minutes of meetings and reports relating to relief activities of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration in China at the end of World War II.
Ray, J. Franklin (Jefferson Franklin), 1905-
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1976.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Contents of Collection
Collection composed of meeting minutes and reports related to the activities of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (U.N.R.R.A.) in China at the end of World War II.
Biographical Note
J. Franklin Ray was an American diplomat who served in several United Nations and State Department positions. From 1945 to 1947 he was the director of the Far East Office of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration. In this position he was responsible for supervising the welfare missions in Australia, China, India, Korea, New Zealand, and the Philippines. Ray was also a member of the 1948 and 1949 delegation to the Far Eastern Commission. From 1951 to 1953 he served in the United States, and United Nations posts dealing with Korean economic development. J. Franklin Ray died on February 22nd, 1991.
United States Relief and Rehabilitation Administration; China.; International relief.; Reconstruction (1939-1951)--China.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Civilian relief.; World War, 1939-1945.
- China Liberated Areas Relief Association, "U.N.R.R.A for the Chinese People", Shanghai, December, 1947 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (U.N.R.R.A.), China Office, Acting Director's morning staff meetings, May-August, 1946 (Box-folder 1: 2-4)
- U.N.R.R.A. China Office, Chiang Kai-shek letter, July 23, 1946 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- U.N.R.R.A, China Office, Director's Morning staff meetings, August-September, 1947 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- U.N.R.R.A. China Office, Monthly Reports, 1946 January - 1947 Januray (Box-folder 1: 7)
- U.N.R.R.A. China Office, Monthly Reports (No.1-7), 1946 January - 1947 January (Box-folder 2: 1)
- U.N.R.R.A. China Office, Monthly Reports, 1946 January - 1947 January (Box-folder 2: 2)
- U.N.R.R.A, China Office, Monthly Reports, 1946 January - 1947 January (Box-folder 2: 9)
- U.N.R.R.A, China Office, Status Sheets, 1946 November - December (Box-folder 2: 3)
- U.N.R.R.A, China Office, Summaries of China Office Reports, 1946 April, June - August (Box-folder 2: 4)
- U.N.R.R.A, China Office, Summaries of China Office Reports, 1947 January - March (Box-folder 2: 5)
- U.N.R.R.A, China Office, Agricultural Rehabilitation Division, "The Agricultural Analyst's Digest", 1947 February, March, May - October (Box-folder 2: 6)
- U.N.R.R.A, China Office, China Office, Agricultural Rehabilitation Division, Monthly Reports, 1946 November (Box-folder 2: 7)
- U.N.R.R.A, China Office, Agricultural Rehabilitation Division, Monthly Reports, 1947 May - July (Box-folder 2: 8)
- U.N.R.R.A, China Office, Agricultural Rehabilitation Division, Weekly Staff Conference, 1947 February (Box-folder 3: 1)
- U.N.R.R.A, China Office, China Office, Agricultural Rehabilitation Division, Weekly Staff Conference, 1947 June - October (Box-folder 3: 2)
- U.N.R.R.A, China Office, Agricultural Rehabilitation Division, Weekly Staff Conference, 1947 November 4 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- U.N.R.R.A, China Office, Agricultural Rehabilitation Division, Weekly Staff Conference, 1947 December 9 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- U.N.R.R.A / C.N.R.R.A.. Liaison Office, Weekly Reports, 1946 July - November (Box-folder 3: 5)